Amit Kumar Mishra

Seeking a beginner role to enhance and explore my knowledge gained at IIIT, Bhubaneswar in the last two years. I am a passionate learner and always try to explore different fields. I have also been part of some open source programs like DevScript Winter of Code and GirlScript Summer of Code.





≥ mamit7503@gmail.com

8688785464

in linkedin.com/in/amit-mishra-28122a193



github.com/Amit366

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology International Institute of Information Technology, Bhubaneswar

06/2019 - Present

9.01

Courses

 Computer Science and Engineering

Intermediate

FIITJEE Junior College, Visakhapatnam

04/2017 - 04/2019

97.2

WORK EXPERIENCE

Open Source Contributor GirlScript Summer of Code

03/2021 - Present

Tasks

- Contributed to various projects like:
- NeoAlgo: Added different data structures and algorithms.
- NeoAlgo-Docs: Added documentations on various algorithms.
- Amazing-Python-Scripts: Added different python scripts which can be used in our daily lives like unzipping a zipped file, PDF to text converter and so on .
- Awesome-Javascript-Projects: Added few javascript projects.

Open Source Contributor

Cross Winter of Code (IEEE DTU)

02/2021 - 02/2021

Tasks

 Contributed to various projects like: IntrepidKey: Added functionality for random password generation and made the website responsive.

Open Source Contributor DevScript Winter of Code

12/2020 - 02/2021

Tasks

- · Contributed to various projects like:
- FireShort: Changed the entire UI of the login page.
- World-Covid-Tracker: Made it a Progressive Web App.
- idea-lab: Made it a Progressive Web App.

Internshala Student Partner Internshala

06/2020 - 08/2020

 Created awareness regarding Internshala in my college and also in different groups through social media.

SKILLS

Web development Active listenina

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Courier Website

- This is a team project where I worked on the backend and some part of frontend. In this website user can register themselves for courier services .
- Here the tech stack used are HTML, CSS and PHP.
- The link to the project: https://github.com/Amit366/CourierWebsite

- This app is a memes sharing app. The app uses an API to fetch different memes when the user clicks on the 'next' button. Here the user can also share the memes on their social media by clicking on 'share'
- The tech stack used is Java.
- The link to the project: https://github.com/Amit366/MemesApp

Birthday Card App

- This is an app in which a happy birthday caption with an image is generated on typing the name of a person.
- The tech stack used is Java.
- The link to the project: https://github.com/Amit366/Birthday_Card_app

ACHIEVEMENTS

I participated in DevScript Winter of Code and secured sixth rank out of 2200 participants.

I participated in Cross Winter of Code and secured second rank out of 300 participants

I was the part of the winning team of ISP 18

LANGUAGES

English Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency

Teluau

Limited Working Proficiency

Odia

Limited Working Proficiency

INTERESTS

Sports

Gaming